A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, David K. Lelewar and Joan Dunlop FA1217
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers, Associates, David K. Lelewar and Joan Dunlop
1969-1977
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
Lelewar, David K.
Dunlop, Joan (1934-2012)
FA1217
2.62 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged material is available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Series 1: David K. Lelewar Files - Commission on Population Growth and the American Future.
Series 2: Joan Dunlop Files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Lelewar and Dunlop collection was donated to RAC by the JDR 3rd estate as a part of the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers.
Scope and Contents
David Lelewar's files pertain specifically to the Commission on Population Growth and the American Future and consist of transcripts of Commission hearings, copies of contract research, and correspondence concerning the organization of the Commission and the publication of its final report.
Joan Dunlop's files document the gradual broadening of John D. Rockefeller 3rd's activities in the 1970s as he moved away from strictly demographic and contraceptive research into the areas of abortion and human sexuality.
- David K. Lelewar Files - Commission on Population Growth and the American Future, 1
  - General Correspondence, Final Report, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commissioners, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charles F. Westoff, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Opposition, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Staff Personnel, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Finances, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meetings, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hearings, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Final Report, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Publicity, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Interim Report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Press Coverage on Release of Final Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Citizens Committee on Population and the American Future - Solicitations for Corporation Contributions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Citizens Committee on Population and the American Future, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Citizens Committee on Population and the American Future - Minutes and Meetings, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - TV, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Key Issues (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Commission on Population Growth and the American Future (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Joan Dunlop Files, 2
  - Papers (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL), 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Committee for the Middle Ground, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Jack Bode, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Human Sexuality, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Senate Subcommittee on Housing, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Senate Subcommitteee on Labor, HEW, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Maude's Dilemma - TV, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Institute for Family Research and Education, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Midwest Association - Study - Human Sexuality, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Center for Social Research, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Population Year and Youth, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Population Conference, Bellagio III, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Health Alternatives, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Health Insurance Legislation, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Grants, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Grants - Population Crisis Committee, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Abortion Rights, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Fatima Mernissi - Papers (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Population - Catholic Church, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Population - Washington, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Black Attitudes Towards Family Planning and Zero Population Growth, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)